Stripe was one of these things that's very obvious looking back, you know, but at the time sort of
took a bit of a zoomed out requirement that I think to come up with. Stripe historically has
thought about here all of these really complicated difficult financial systems that have built for
all sorts of probably justifiable reasons, you know, and here's kind of a simple API to go and
interact with them, you know, and then kind of here comes crypto and and now sort of stablecoin
specifically, and just said well let's forget about all of that, right? What if we just rebuilt
it from first principles to be digital money, and I think that that's that's really kind of a good
capture is Stripe has been this for the traditional finance world, which is what really makes us so
well positioned to also be this for this new world that's coming today. Welcome to epicenter,
the show which talks about the technologies projects and people driving decentralization
and the blockchain revolution. I am Frederica Anst and today I'm speaking with John Egan who
is the head of crypto at Stripe. Stripe of course builds payments payment infrastructure for the
internet and is one of the most valuable fintechs worldwide. Before I talk with John, let me tell
you about our sponsors this week. If you're looking to stake your crypto with confidence,
look no further than chorus 1. More than 150,000 delegators including institutions like BitGo,
Pentera Capital and Ledger trust chorus 1 with their assets, they support over 50 blockchains
and are leaders in governance on networks like Cosmos ensuring your stake is responsibly managed.
Thanks to their advanced MEV research you can also enjoy the highest staking rewards.
You can stake directly from your preferred wallet, set up a white label note,
re-stake your assets on eigenneo or symbiotic or use the SDK for multi-chain staking in your app.
Learn more at chorus.1 and start staking today.
This episode is proudly brought to you by Gnosis, a collective dedicated to advancing
a decentralized future. Gnosis leads innovation with circles, gnosis pay and metric, reshaping,
open banking and money. With Hashi and Gnosis VPN, they're building a more resilient privacy
focus internet. If you're looking for an L1 to launch your project, Gnosis Chain offers the same
development environment as Ethereum with lower transaction fees. It's supported by over 200,000
validators making Gnosis Chain a reliable and credibly neutral foundation for your applications.
Gnosis DAO drives Gnosis governance where every voice matters. Join the Gnosis community in the
Gnosis DAO forum today. Deploy on the EVN compatible Gnosis Chain or secure the network
with just one GNO and affordable hardware. Start your decentralization journey today at Gnosis DAIO.
Hey, John, thank you so much for coming on. Hey, thanks for having me.
I know you are currently on Stripe Tour. Where are you calling in from?
I'm calling in from New York today, which is where a good chunk of the Stripe crypto team is
actually based, but pretty soon we'll actually be out in Berlin doing that segment of Stripe Tour
and then really all over the world for the rest of the year all the way up until the New York Tour,
which happens in November. So big, big moment for Stripe to go around and really reach out and
interact with merchants and sort of explain the new features, mostly that we launched at sessions
and to go deep. So really, really excited to do it and it's going to be a packed schedule.
Super cool. Maybe before we dive into Stripe and Web3, tell us a bit about yourself and kind of
like where your career took you so far. I know kind of you were previously at Facebook and also at
early startup, some of which you actually co-founded. Tell us about that.
Yeah, sure. So I'm an engineer by training. I thought I'd go and build robots.
And that turned out to be a little bit of a slow industry. So got out of that, ended up
getting into startups or an OIC startup in high-speed data transport way back in 2011. It feels like
forever ago now. And that company was bought by Facebook, which is how I ended up there.
And at Facebook, built all kinds of tools and infrastructure for the organization as it was
growing. It ultimately took over and ran the workplace team. I've founded that with Lars Rismusen
over there. Ran that out of London and sort of grew that up to be one of Stripe's major enterprise,
sorry, Facebook's major enterprise pillars. Came back here to New York. And that's around when I
started to get into blockchain in 2016, where I founded an NFT company called Additional Wayback
Before NFTs. Anyone cared about them. I remember going up and down Santel Road and being told by
every investor that NFTs would never be interesting and never a thing for exciting. But we were like
an iPhone app. So we were like the Instagram for NFTs. And it was really fun. It was really
early stage. Lots of digital artists and digital creation and distribution. And I was just like
super excited about the kind of decentralized and open network nature of blockchain. Ethereum was
just happening at the time and was kind of having its first kind of groundswell of developer
excitement and applications being built. And then pivoted out of that into an incident response
company for a little while, taking some of the learnings from Fang. And frankly, blockchain,
if you really want to have like a great history of incidents, you work in crypto for a while.
And then, you know, after that pivot, I really wanted to get back into the crypto space. I really
love the people. I love the technology. You know, we have this kind of saying in crypto, I'm sure,
you know, it's like, good morning, everything's early, right? And that's just the best space to
be in for technology. And so when I did the math, you know, and sort of worked out, well, what company
do I think is going to have the greatest impact, you know, on the world, you know, to take this
technology that was emerging? That just naturally brought me to Stripe where I found that there was
a kind of young and rapidly growing crypto organization. And I joined about two years ago and took over
that team and been running it ever since. Yeah, that takes us all the way through to Stripe.
I think kind of how big and pervasive Stripe is in the payments ecosystem
is a well-kept secret because kind of like a lot of this is abstracted away from
normal users, right? So kind of for listeners who only see Stripe kind of in conjunction with
kind of like credit card buttons, how would you describe Stripe's mission and kind of your
cool offerings? Yeah, so look, first of all, I think a lot of that's by design, right? If you
think about Stripe kind of from a user standpoint, we take this very complicated world of, you know,
centralized finance, right? Let's not talk about blockchain. Yeah, but like all of these kind of
siloed parts of the traditional finance world, and we simplify them, right? Down to APIs and
interfaces and UX that, you know, merchants can go and integrate in a couple of lines of code
without having to think about all the like complicated money movement that's happening
under the hood. Interesting personal piece of history. I have one of the first hundred Stripe
accounts. I was in Y Combinator a couple of classes after John and Patrick, and I remember
getting an email from John. I think back then it was called dev payments. It was like they hadn't
named themselves Stripe yet. And the pitch was, you know, so simple. It was just, listen, we've had
tons of trouble just doing payment processing for our company. You know, we've decided to make it
a lot easier. You know, here's an API. Click here to sign up. And you know, I think what was actually
happening, you know, in the back end, as they were opening merchant accounts kind of manually,
they were sending a lot of mail back and forth, you know, but, but, but I remember as a founder at
the time, I hadn't even thought about how I was going to make payments work. I just assumed it was
easy because when you work in technology, you get really comfortable with the idea that everything's
internet native, right? Of course, there's an API. Of course, there's a GitHub page. Of course,
there's some like simple thing that I can build, but the reality was there wasn't for payments. You
needed to go work with a bank. You had to open these complicated merchant accounts. So I actually
think that very early sort of simplicity of the way that Stripe was presented as this is the fast lane,
right? Into all of these things that you just need to do to run your business actually still
are present today. And today, it's just that fast lane is now access to a lot more than payments,
right? We call it just financial infrastructure. So everything from, you know, card issuing to,
you know, now after after sessions, you know, money management and storage, you know, to loans.
And in fact, you can even create companies on Stripe, right? You can go to Atlas. So if you're,
if you're at the very beginning of like a startup accelerator, you're probably at Stripe well before
you even start to take payments. And now it's not just an API, right? We have like the integrated
checkout suite. That's all the UX and we have with the lemon squeezy acquisition, right? We have like
progress towards like merchant of record. There's all these like amazing capabilities. I'm only
probably touching like 1% of what the company does. But really, that's what it should be, right?
As an engineer, especially in the valley, you know, that's every, it's just an assumption. Of course,
you're going to come and use Stripe. This is the best and easiest and most well-documented,
you know, and self-service product for accessing all of these complicated financial systems that
you really do need to be able to leverage to grow a business, you know, from a couple of dollars of
test revenue up to billions. I'm sure we'll get into this in just a little bit. But Stripe is very
much a bundler, right? Kind of like it, it abstracts a lot of the complexity that is,
that's kind of integral to kind of the payments stack and kind of like all these various things,
kind of like you can do kind of with money on the internet. Behind kind of your smartly kind of
collated APR is, why is it so complex? Can you kind of give us some insights into that? And I
think kind of like we'll dive into that when we talk about kind of like the crypto aspect of this
later. But often kind of you think in principle, this should be easy, right? Kind of like sending
money to a merchant should not require kind of the world's most expensive fintech to kind of
do this for you, right? Right, right. Yeah. So the history of money, right, is really really
just what leads us here. It's a long and complicated history, very like closely mapped to like the
creation of society. And so just like we have all of these, you can almost map money down to culture.
Right, how many thousands of cultures do we have in the world? And each culture sort of grew out
of a siloed set of humans coming up with ways that they wanted to transact with each other.
It's maybe like the very simplest way to kind of think about like the evolution of early commerce.
And all of these rules got built inside of each of these cultures and each of these silos to define
what it means to transact not just money, but assets in general, right? What does it mean to
move value from like one human to another, one human to a corporation, right? One corporation
to another corporation, you know, into real world assets or sort of these complex financial
instruments that eventually grew. And you almost have to replay, you know, these hundreds of years
of history to catch up to why it's so complicated today, right? In the US, why do we have been sponsors,
you know, for processing credit card transactions, but in other countries, maybe we don't. Let's
just sort of a trick of where of the history of how credit cards evolved in this country versus
how they evolved in the rest of the world. You know, why do we have certain types of regulated,
you know, banking systems? And every country has a different answer, right? Like, why was it
developed in Germany, you know, for a specific set of rules? I'm sure entirely different than
why the state of New York manages its money and sort of rules for its banking organizations.
And I think like, when you kind of carry that all forward, you just get a lot of complexity.
And then you get a lot of players who are trying to work to do interconnection at different points
in history. So what it meant to go and interconnect banks 20 years ago through like these correspondent
banking networks, right? It was pretty different from how we'd probably connect banks if we were
doing it today. And we're really starting to, you know, sort of see that with stablecoins especially
in kind of crypto networks. But, you know, all of these problems have always existed and there
have always been people trying to solve those problems for the world. And I think Stripe was
really just the first internet oriented company to solve this problem, right? And it was, it was
very much a, there were systems to go and get merchant accounts at banks. And there certainly
were middlemen back there to go back then to go and do it. But none of them were just a forum on
the internet, you know, that you filled out and that then returned an API key, you know, back to
you. So I think Stripe was, Stripe was one of these things that's very obvious looking back,
you know, but at the time sort of took a bit of a zoomed out requirement, I think, to come up with.
Not to put words in John and Patrick's mouths. I'm sure they've talked about the history of the
company many times. But, you know, funny story, when I was first onboarding here, you know,
crypto wasn't in the best spot a couple of years ago. You know, we had a couple of major collapses.
There were, there were, you know, some sort of scary, almost moments of near deepag even in
the stablecoin world. And in my onboarding class, there was a moment where John kind of came on
and would just sort of take Q&A from everywhere. And I just sort of was quietly keeping my mouth shut
in the back on the zoom. But someone else, someone, someone completely unassociated with crypto
asked him, you know, about crypto, you know, and sort of how he thinks about it. And he said,
I think what's kind of getting at your point, which was, you know, Stripe historically has thought
about here, all of these really complicated, difficult financial systems that have built for
all sorts of probably justifiable reasons. You know, and here's kind of a simple API to go and
interact with them, you know, and then kind of here comes crypto and now sort of stablecoin
specifically. And just said, well, let's forget about all of that, right? What if we just rebuilt
it from first principles to be digital money? And I think that that's, that's really kind of a good
capture is Stripe has been this for the traditional finance world, which is what really makes us so
well positioned to also be this for this new world that's coming today. Stripe kind of saw the
potential for digital currencies super early on. So you guys started accepting Bitcoin over
10 years ago in 2014. Can you talk about what motivated that decision and also kind of, I know
it was before your time at Stripe. But kind of, you also kind of, Stripe also wound down its
Bitcoin support just a couple of years later, kind of like, and only started engaging with
the crypto ecosystem again years later. So maybe, maybe, um, talk us through kind of like this
very early exploration of, um, of crypto rates for payments. Yeah, I think, I think like most
technologies, you know, they're, they're, they're a couple of, I won't call Bitcoin a false start
because Bitcoin's doing wonderfully. Um, but at least in terms of exploring it from a, from a
payments rail standpoint, you know, I think, I think we, we, when Stripe originally got into the
space, there's a lot of excitement about this, this technology really just catching on, um,
becoming more, more accessible. You know, we were far enough along that most people had heard about
Bitcoin. It was certainly demand, you know, to use it as a payment method. Um, but the reality is,
and I think last year at Sessions, John Carlson sort of addressed this very directly on stage
when we were announcing that we were coming back with, with stablecoin payments, you know, the,
the downside was, you know, almost twofold. Um, one, everyone really regrets every Bitcoin they ever
spent. I'm not, I'm not sure about you, but, but I rented a hotel in, uh, in, in France, you know,
back in like 20, I think it was around 20, 2014, 2015. Um, and I think I look back and I probably
spent effectively, you know, $60,000 a night on that hotel, you know, probably not the best,
the best, like, feeling to have after, after, you know, engaging in commerce or a transaction. Um,
and second of all, look, the user experience just wasn't great. You know, we have high expectations
because despite how poor and complex the, the traditional finance world is, there's a lot of,
like, virtualization that's already happened. You know, I was talking about how there's a lot of
players in this space today, you know, to, to make us consumers feel like that's not the case,
right? So, so I can, I can walk into a coffee shop and I can tap a card, right? And I get my coffee
right away. You know, there's always been this joke, the day you can finally buy coffee with
cryptocurrency will be the day that, that we've won. And 2014, you know, was not that date. You
know, if you wanted to buy something, you know, online, you'd sort of make the checkout experience,
and we'd say, oh, we'll get back to you. You know, it's, it'll, it'll finish in a little bit,
right? And we would wait for sort of the next set of blocks to be processed, and the, and the
transaction to be secured, and then we would send an email, and then you would come back,
and it was just a very complicated process. And consumers, listen, if my time at, at, at
meta really taught me anything, consumers do not have patience, you know, for anything less than
instant. You know, maybe a few seconds if there's high conviction. And I think ultimately, just for
those practical reasons, it was simply not a great payment method. And usage was not really there.
And so Stripe, if anything, is a practical company, despite being being, you know, very,
have very head in the clouds when we're sort of dreaming here. And I think the, the, the decision
was made reasonably quickly, you know, a couple of years later to, to cancel that as a payment
method. And we waited, you know, very patiently until the technology caught up to the point where
we could do the demo that was done at sessions where it was just like, okay, don't blink. Here
we go. Click done. And I think that that sort of piece of magic was missing. And, and so, so yeah,
that's that's, that's kind of been the history there. Skips over some of the other work we've done,
we're like just enabling the web three economies through things like on ramps. And we still do
offer a crypto on ramp to help sort of specifically crypto wallets on board consumers and participate
in these, these, these new areas of commerce, especially, you know, people are experimenting
with DAOs and NFTs had a really big moment for a while there. So Stripe's been sort of in and
around the space consistently since at least 2014. But I really think that this moment is sort of
the most native to Stripe's mission with, with stablecoins coming onto the scene. And I think
that's why we're being a lot noisier about it now. I think it's a much more exciting time.
If you kind of had to point your finger at one set of events that kind of made you say,
okay, the time is now, what, what would that be? You know, I went to, I think the first,
the first year I was here about two years ago, I went to, I think it was ETH CC.
And, you know, in previous kind of crypto conferences that we've been to, you know,
really all of the focus was on sort of those topics I was mentioning before, you know,
we really everyone was building a new NFT marketplace or everyone was building,
you know, a new wallet, right? But I remember at ETH CC, there was this surprising undercurrent
of stablecoins starting to pop up. And I, you know what, I can't actually even peg why.
It was just something we started to notice. You know, I think there was, I believe there was like
beginning talks of sort of like Mika back then and kind of like some regulatory conversations
that were happening. And so that was sort of starting to spur this conversation about like
regulatory impact on these tokens and how they might be used. I think we met with a,
we met with a couple of folks sort of who are working towards that goal, you know, around like
circle and we talked to, I think, Bonarium back then and a couple of other organizations. And
everyone was aware of Tether and kind of its global impact. But that was the first time that I
actually heard the developer community talking about it. I really think kind of the slowdown
in the NFT space gave everyone sort of a moment to breathe and think back towards, okay, what,
what technology shifts are happening, what like opportunities are going to be for all of us
developers over the next couple of years. And when I came back and I wrote my notes up on that
conference, it was, it was at the very top. And I sort of just had like a general note that was
like, oh, stablecoins, we should, we should really keep an eye on those. Like maybe we should start
to build more in that space. So I, you know, it wasn't really like an aha moment and like I was
making a transaction and the person next to me used a stablecoin. And I saw how amazing it was.
It was actually much more developer led, which I think is a lot of what happens in crypto.
And it's sort of exciting is everyone just sort of quietly starts to talk about it.
And then everyone starts to build. And then we get this kind of magical moment. And certainly
there'd been a lot happening before that, right? Like the origins of stablecoins and
cross border commerce that we were seeing out of existing companies. But that was, that was kind
of the first conference where I came away feeling like maybe it was starting to become
something that developers would care a lot about. And that's generally the, the beginning,
right? Of starting to see interesting opportunities.
One of your previous startups, the, the NFT project, which was also built on Ethereum. So,
and you went to ECC. So kind of like, was there always kind of this focus on the Ethereum space?
Or kind of like, what's your, what's your network strategy? So I know kind of like,
the, your current offerings in the crypto space on base, right? So how, how, how do you navigate
this territory? Because kind of it can be pretty fraught, right?
Yeah. So we're, we're network agnostic. I mean, I, I list ECC just because it's one of the larger
conferences. And I think Ethereum developers were at the time, especially like sort of on the forefront
of like these programmable applications and layers. But look, across our products, you know,
we support Ethereum, you know, Polygon, Solana, base, Stellar, you know, we have a pretty wide
ranging list of different networks that we interop with. And I think, I, Aptos pretty recently,
you know, we, we don't, we don't really think about it in terms of like this network or that
network needs to win. We are, we are technologists who will take advantage of whatever is available
to us at the time. You know, we are very excited about what base is doing. You know, we, we use
base and in the stablecoin financial account product that we just announced at sessions. But
yeah, I think the same thing with, with the coin strategy, to be quite honest, it's a common question
that Stripe gets, you know, what is, what is your coin strategy, which coins are you using? And,
you know, right now on the stablecoin front, we're pretty focused on, on USDC, kind of as a publicly
tradable coin, you know, with the acquisition of bridge, we now have USDB as kind of an internal
infrastructure coin, which is pretty exciting. There's a lot, lots to dig into there from a
technology standpoint and kind of opportunity. You know, and then, and then certainly we're aware
of like the other large players in the space, like Tether, and kind of how those will start to play
out as the regulatory environment changes. But no, I don't, I don't, I, I'm a big fan of Ethereum,
you know, and I think at the time, especially when I was building my startup, that was kind of,
if you were going to build an app, you'd go get what was it back then Truffle? I think it was like
the, the sort of like, like developer tool set you would download to sort of experiment.
From consensus, yeah. Right, yeah, yeah. And, and so I think that was just like where these
conversations were growing out of. You know, we did start to hear about it also in the Solana
conferences was another one. I think that was starting to emerge then it is now becoming like
particularly interesting from a developer standpoint. So what, what are kind of the minimum requirements
you kind of have for network integration, right? Kind of like, I mean, you could look at security
and performance and, uh, uh, level of decentralization and so on. What, what are the things? Or do you,
do you guys say, look, we, we purely go by, by user need, um, and kind of because in some way,
kind of like building on these rails, you, you can never be more resilient than the rails themselves,
right? Right. Um, gosh, how do we think about this? I think, I think we take a pretty practical stance.
Um, you know, we have, we have, we have a strong compliance posture at the company.
I think stripe, we've always thought of ourselves as the honest broker of this space and we need,
you know, our largest users to be able to look to us confidently. So certainly there's a compliance
layer here, which is we need to be able to do, you know, the basic checks, right? The sanctions
checks and the, and the transaction monitoring and all of these kinds of like basic requirements
for being able to kind of interop with, uh, with, with legal businesses across the world, you know,
but really past that, we're just watching for consumer and merchant demand. Um, you know, I,
I think, I think this is shifting a little bit, but we're not really the evangelists of the space,
right? We are, we are, we are utility providers helping to connect, you know, merchants to this
capability set. And so I think, you know, we probably have fewer, you know, chains and coins
than, you know, your average decentralized exchange would expose. Um, but I think that that's okay.
I think for now, like we don't necessarily have to have a thousand different chains
available or a thousand different coins. What's important is that we give people this sort of
high quality experience that they can rely on. Um, and so, you know, that, that, that, that maps
down to kind of the, the top, I hate to use the word like blue chip, but you know, sort of the top,
you know, coins on the top networks and frankly, the most well regulated ones as well. Um,
listen, I'm, I'm sitting in New York right now. And if you go pull up the NY DFS is green list,
right? There's only a subset of coins and networks that we can provide to people in this state.
And I think that is changing rapidly and adapting throughout the world. But we're just, we're
pragmatists when it comes to that stuff. You know, I don't, I don't, I don't think that we have too,
too much of a dog in the fight specifically. And certainly if, you know, our largest merchants come
to us asking about a specific coin or a specific network, you know, just like we would for any
traditional product, we would go and explore that and integrate it. We skipped over this part a
little bit earlier. Tell us about, um, the services you kind of offer kind of on Web3, right? You,
you mentioned a stable coin financial product and so on, but maybe let's, let's go, go through
them one by one. Yeah, I can put my marketing hat on for a minute. Um, so, so we have all kinds of
really cool services right now is specifically in the stable coin space. Um, you know, the, the,
the banner services are kind of native to the stripe products that we already, you would already
expect them to be attached to. So for example, um, we have a pay-ins product, which if you have
stripes, uh, OCS, a checkout suite, uh, integrated, you can offer your consumers the ability to pay
with stable coins across a series of different networks, um, and coins. And you can do that just
like any other LPM. You can go into your payment method settings. You can click a button thing,
bang, boom. Now you can pay with, with stable coins. So pretty large product there. Uh,
you know, powering, uh, most recently, uh, big announcement with Shopify, uh, rolling out two
millions of Shopify merchants powering from, uh, behind the scenes with shop pay. Uh, we also have
a payouts product, which is sort of the opposite of this. Maybe about pay-ins as a way to get global
consumers to be able to pay your business in, say, the U S payouts is the other way around.
Whole world wants access to the, to dollars, especially if you're running a digital marketplace
or maybe a global global gig economy. You can use the payouts product with stable coins to distribute,
uh, dollar peg stable coins to users anywhere around the world. Um, you also have a global
treasury product that is really offered more through our, our acquisition with bridge,
which is all about managing, uh, your global treasury and money. Uh, SpaceX is sort of the
example that comes up all the time here, this sort of like global operation that needs to move all
of their money back into dollars efficiently and easily every day. Um, that's more of like a low
level API integrated service. Um, and then we've also, uh, have some really interesting products
that we're building around money management and storage, most recently the stable coin
financial accounts, which is if you think about, okay, now you have pay-ins and you have pay-outs,
but where do you store that money? So Stripe, uh, released a general money management suite,
uh, at sessions. And as part of that, we're also offering stable coin storage. And what's
really exciting about that is it's not just storage in kind of our existing 50 or so markets,
it's 101 net new markets in which you can now store dollars with Stripe. And these accounts have
access to US and EU rails as well. So if you need to pull money and you can do it over wire,
ACH or SEPA. Um, and then I think maybe, maybe the one other big announcement recently was, uh,
stable coin backed card issuing, um, which similar to stable coin financial accounts is sort of
available globally and allows you to issue debit cards that are backed by stable coins. So all
of these, all of these pieces kind of come together pretty magically, but really what you should be
able to do is approach Stripe and think about all of the services we offer today through a lens of
what if I wanted global access and dollar access specifically through stable coins. And you should
be able to find that I think you already kind of scattered over this. But when you look at the
tools that kind of you offer on crypto rails and kind of you compare them to the tools you offer
on, um, on traditional finance rails, how would you compare the two? Oh, I don't like to think of
them as different. I, you know, they're, they're sort of at the limit, stable coins should really
be thought of as just another currency, right? And then, and then under the hood, like at least
for, from the standpoint of like a user interacting with our products, and then under the hood,
everything should be faster and more integrated and, and, and hopefully less expensive thanks to
the infrastructure. But you know, when, when my example on payons, I think is sort of my favorite
one for this, right? You, you shouldn't have to go to a different company, a different website,
a different experience, just to be able to offer payons as a type of payment, right? We think about
this as like a global LPM. And just like if you were a merchant and you wanted to accept, um, you
know, swish, uh, in, in Sweden, I believe, uh, you would just go to a payment method page and click
a button and the switch would flip and it would show up on the checkout screen for the appropriate
folks. The same thing is true for stablecoin acceptance, which is you are already processing
probably cards or otherwise, and you just want to expand your consumer reach. You can go to the
settings page, you can click the button, turn it on. That's kind of like, I think the, the, the bar,
right? It should just be part of the experience. And I really think this is, this is kind of the
opportunity stripe has maybe versus what, what's been offered historically from other organizations
is you shouldn't have to go integrate another product or another service. You should be able to
just do it within the experience you already have today. Um, you know, our users are running
businesses that have, uh, usually centered, not around payments, right? Not really centered around
some other interesting consumer V2B opportunity and creation. Um, and so I guess, I guess that's
like, that's the bar, you know, for, for some of these products that are, that are certainly more
complex where we're powering, say, a FinTech. You know, in those worlds, we are kind of back to the
API integration layer. Um, and I think in those worlds, that's what's most effective. You know,
bridge, bridge is a great example of this. If you want to really deeply integrate, you know,
virtual accounts and you want to deeply integrate like money movement and you have even maybe some
customer requirements that you want to work with the bridge team in terms of integrating, um, you
also have that option now, which is to come to stripe and say, you know, I want to go very close
to the metal, right? And I want to enable sort of very unique and powerful money movement systems
to build my FinTech app or otherwise. And I think, I think we're going to see that split exist for a
while in the stablecoin space. It should be something that's kind of easy and instant for the vast
majority of the world who's just trying to kind of turn these things on and make an enable on top
of services they already have. And then you're going to have these kind of close to the metal,
you know, super APIs that will allow you to go and create the FinTechs of the future.
And I think that's that's probably the right split, right? You sort of want a little bit of a
choose your own adventure here. If you're selling, you know, a shipped product through a tiktok
marketing campaign, right? Or, you know, if you're building a, you know, a Robinhood or something
like that. Yeah, maybe a revolution. Yeah, that makes that makes a lot of sense for the merchants
themselves. So there's I would argue that there's a very small set of customers who were unavailable
to them previously, right? Kind of like there's very few people who say I will pay in Stables and
Stables only. So does the experience kind of become better for the merchants if you pay them in Stables?
Because in principle, kind of like you could make this faster and cheaper. So kind of like one of the
one of the main pain points for merchants and kind of like accepting card payments is often
that kind of like they actually set a weeks later, right? So kind of like and in principle,
kind of like on crypto raids, you can make it almost instant. So kind of like what's the upside for
the merchant? Yeah, so I do actually think there's a pretty large port, just to challenge the very
first statement. I do actually think there's a large and growing group of consumers who would
prefer to pay with Stablecoins, especially in geographic regions that were previously unreachable,
you know, by the card networks. Especially as we see kind of a growth of digital services,
you know, one of our like large users of pay-ins and pay-outs is sort of a digital
trading organization. And that's success all over the world, you know, from Africa to Asia
to to the US. And in that environment, you're actually doing like net new consumer reach. So I
do actually think there's a pretty strong angle there. But outside of that, there's sort of two
other categories, right? One is, you know, merchants are looking for, to your point, you know, a faster
ability to settle kind of inbound. And they're also looking for, you know, especially US merchants
are looking for sort of like local currency, right? Payment rails. So how do I process everything in
in dollars globally, right? Without necessarily having to deal with, say, the FX coming from these
regions that I'm otherwise transacting with. But I think the settlement side is actually a good one
to dig into just in general from a business operations standpoint. And the amount of time
that you have to wait for an average credit card settlement can be, you know, days, the amount of
time you have to wait for cross-border payments, you know, it can be days to weeks depending on the
networks that are in between, you know, with a stablecoin payment, you should be able to operate
and you can operate, you know, near instantly. And, you know, maybe in the worst case, a couple of hours.
And I think like that capability has business operations benefits, whereas sort of like the
consumer reach just has sort of like business, you know, revenue reach benefits. And I think just
like any, any good disruptive technology, right, you can put a bunch of different lenses on this
thing and say, okay, what are these specific reasons that this is going to work better for
my organization? And I think if you take like a digital marketplace, that reach might be the
thing that's most interesting. Or if you take a small, you know, startup that's maybe a little
bit cash strapped, right, the settlement time might become more important. You know, and then if you
take, take other types of organizations kind of in the middle, there's actually a simplicity layer,
which is like, can I just turn on this like one new capability and still run my business in dollars
without having to think about all the different LPMs. So I think there's like three or four different
lenses you can put on it. And they all sort of just add up to the process product being better.
I think again, like I come back to this point a lot. A lot of this is just sort of happening,
like the number of businesses and consumers transacting in stablecoins is growing anyway,
and providing that capability is something that just like if there was another credit card
network that was growing really quickly, we'd have merchants knocking down our doors saying,
you know, why don't you support this new network? It's very similar. You know, what is what is the
volume? It's like seven, seven point three trillion, I think is like the yearly adjusted
transaction volume. And if you actually take the like, unadjusted volume, I think I've
written down here, it's like 34 trillion dollars, which exceeds like the combined value of the two
credit card networks in terms of transacted volume. So this, this, this trend is occurring
anyway. And like merchants will always want to reach into, you know, whatever financial capabilities
their consumers or their buyers are adopting. And I think sometimes it's almost hard for us to
even know the exact reasons, right? Like there is, there's certainly the crypto natives, right,
that have kind of ended up in stablecoins after years of trading other types of volatile assets.
But there's also just this like rapid global growth of dollar access demand that we're seeing,
especially across like Latin America, where this is the currency that they hold that's most
transactable. And then you get this benefit on the other side of like settlement and business
operations and money movement and treasury management. We've talked about dollars a lot
now. And kind of like when it comes down, I mean, it is the globally dominant currency. But
kind of there's 400 million Americans and there's 8 billion non US residents. What are your thoughts
on non US dollar staples? So today, the stablecoin market, I think it's like 99.9. I don't know if
there's a second, fourth nine there, you know, in dollars. And, you know, I think, I think
being a practical actor, that that means great. So, so we can almost look at the stablecoin market
today and say, okay, it's dollars. And then it's various sort of versions of dollars, right? It's
like if you if you look across say, you know, a circle versus like a tether, you know, versus some
of the other stablecoins that are coming onto the market, you know, what actually backs it and
pegs it to the dollar is a little bit of variance. You know, are you getting yield back when you're
holding them or otherwise? In terms of like the the growth of non dollar stablecoins,
I think it's pretty exciting. Like, I think I think it would be embraced in general. If you
think about, you know, the complexities, we haven't talked at all, by the way, about like on and off
ramping into these things, which is its own like huge challenge, right? But like, like really,
if you look at that, there's there's two lenses to look at it, right? One is to say, okay, how do we
on ramp from the local currency into the dollar, right? Which is really, we're just right back to
the FX problem, right? There's some some like centralized actor there somewhere like defining
the FX, you know, as you come in, you know, maybe it's a crypto exchange, so it's more efficient.
You know, but in the future, I do expect that there will be significantly more local stablecoins
that are issued locally and have kind of that connectivity back into the traditional finance
world through like the bank that's backing the issuing. And then the actual effects can happen
on chain, right? So you like on ramp into, say, the digital euro, and then you transact from the
digital euro into the dollar in an on-chain FX environment that's potentially more, hopefully,
the limit significantly more, you know, efficient than you'd otherwise have. I think taken to the
limit, that gets pretty exciting, right? If we actually have all of these different coins,
you know, mimicking their local currencies globally, then you get a really interesting
effect of sort of broad-scale global decentralized FX, which, again, should be significantly more
efficient for getting into those local currencies, which people still rely on. You know, it's a bit
naive to say, okay, great, you know, your organization, you know, in Brazil, like only needs dollars,
you know, you maybe were primarily transacting, perhaps they want to store there, but the reality
is at the end of the day, they need to get back into local currency, probably to pay their local
employees, to pay their rent, if nothing else. And so I think that, like, space is getting pretty
exciting. And I'm personally really excited about the idea of a pretty large-scale decentralized FX
market, just because I think it'll do what stablecoins have otherwise done, which will be increased
access directly to the market, as opposed to having to go through, you know, layers and layers of
middlemen. I used to tell the story of, at Stripe, all the meeting rooms have like the meetings that
are happening, you know, printed on the digital screen outside of them, and where the crypto team
used to be based in our old office. There was one room next to us, and every morning, it had this
really scary meeting title that was like, there's like daily FX global risk stand-up. It's just like,
like, very scary title happened every morning at like 9 a.m. And I used to try and, you know,
sit close to that room just to hear what was happening. But I think, you know, these markets
aren't always running 24 hours a day. They have difficulty in liquidity. Stripe is having to make
these decisions about where are we holding our money to make sure that we can settle to the local
merchants at some rate that's faster than it would take to go through the banking networks to get
there. In a world of local stablecoins, those problems really fade away. And treasury management,
you know, selfishly for us, but preferably for all businesses just becomes easier, right? It's a,
it's the same thing that has happened across, this is a strange analogy. But, you know, every other
part of, of, of Internet commerce, you know, hotel tonight, right? We don't, we don't book our
hotels days in advance. I would expect the same thing to happen in, in finance. We shouldn't have
to think about how much money we need in a specific currency days in advance. We should be able to
say, great, there's a local stablecoin there. We can transact in a decentralized nature instantly
to get there. And then if we really need to off ramp into the local currency, there's a local
financial institution that's backing that currency that makes off ramps simple. So I think that that
space will be a huge tailwind to the wider stablecoin ecosystem. And I think I imagine where we are
today, where it's all dollars is kind of analogous to the early Internet. Okay, for a while, a lot of
this was coming out of the US and almost all of it was English. And now we have a very much more
interesting and diverse Internet. I think it's the same thing. Walk us through the experience that
kind of a match and today has kind of when they accept staples, right? So kind of say, I'm a
TikTok influencer and I sell something on kind of like a custom website. And I have a stripe
integration and accept staples. So kind of you, you accept US dollar staples on my behalf and then
kind of like, how, how do I actually then get them? Do I have the option to kind of just get the,
get the stables from you? Because in principle, you could kind of just send them on to kind of
like a wallet of my choosing, right? Or kind of like, do I need to have them off ramped into
a traditional bank account? So today, when you stablecoin acceptance is available primarily to
US merchants today, expanding very soon. And all stables that are paid into a striped checkout
experience settle to Fiat. So our merchants today are accustomed to storing in Fiat. And so they,
the easiest way to make this appear like any other LPM that their local payment method that
they're accustomed to accepting is to settle into dollars. Now what's kind of cool is in the most
recent integration with Shopify, powering shop pay, those merchants for the first time actually
have a choice. They can settle into, into USDC directly, I believe on base. Or they can choose
to settle into Fiat. And so that is the direction this is going. So today, primarily settlement down
to Fiat, just to map the kind of user experience that the merchants are accustomed to and to like
lower the friction of number of things you have to learn when you're coming on board.
As a merchant who's accepting stablecoins, but as we think about this more globally,
that stops making sense, right? Like especially in countries where the merchants would primarily
prefer to store and say dollars, but can't today, they have to settle to their local currency.
Like the natural capability, and you can, you can squint a little bit and imagine our roadmap
when you think about like stablecoin financial accounts that are rolling out, this is the capability
that should be there, right? You should also be able to store down into stablecoins. So today,
stores down to Fiat, Shopify merchants, the choice of either, future choice of either for anyone.
And what about expanding these stable integrations for other jurisdictions outside of the US? Because
I imagine, I mean, I understand that kind of the pain points for merchants in the US, particularly
big because kind of the fees on credit cards are often higher than in some other jurisdictions.
So for instance, I think in Europe, they are pretty tightly regulated. But I imagine that
lots of merchants worldwide would love to accept some sort of stable. What's the blocker for you
guys? I mean, in principle, it seems like you have this feature. Why can't you roll it out?
Right, right. So to be clear, the most recent, the Shopify integration, which is available to
those merchants, that is actually globally available. So that's available. And I believe it's like 40
or 50 countries. So we're already doing it. This is sort of the like, the nice way to answer it.
The complicated answer to your question is, you know, it's just integration and rollout timing.
So availability of these products, you know, per country, per like local financial rail,
especially where we want to support direct settlement to those local currencies is just just product
build time. So it has nothing to do with with us not wanting to have it there. And I think Shopify
was the first real big step towards being able to support that with the PANS integration. But you
should expect global availability of this product in the very near future versus it being something
specific to stripe that we would we would ever choose not to. In fact, in fact, actually, the
stablecoin financial accounts are a really great example of where this is almost happening in sort
of an unusual way, right? It was actually the fastest method for us to go and release this
product was to release it and all the country stripes not in yet. It's actually a little bit
easier to go and say, okay, let's let's go, you know, it took us 15 years to get from like one
to 50 countries. But it took us 15 months to get from 50 to 151. So I think like, like that's the
kind of disruption that we just like everyone are sort of learning how to wield is exactly like
what order of operations should we roll things out to which countries. But but yes, stablecoin
PANS, we expect to be available to all stripe supported countries, plus these 101 countries
that we've rolled a stablecoin financial accounts out to in the very near future.
Jori said that kind of on and off rams are clearly a huge pain point for the ecosystem,
right? Kind of like, and if you zoom way out and you kind of think about kind of
blockchain infrastructure as the next evolution in kind of how financial rates will work,
kind of building good on and off ramping experiences is absolutely crucial, right? Because kind of
like quite frankly, legacy finance financial products is where all of the values and kind of,
yes, we have super cool protocols and so on in in web three, but kind of like, a lot of the problem
is how do you actually get the value across, right? So talk us through how you see that
problem set today and how you see it evolve. Yeah, look, we are clearly in the dial up era
of like on and off ramps globally, depending on the country that you're in, let's just take,
let's even take the US as an example, even even in the US, it's reasonably difficult for your
average consumer who has never held any sort of stablecoin or crypto asset to get on chain the first
time. You know, as we provide an on ramp that I think lowers this barrier pretty significantly,
but even there, you know, you're sort of going through a KYC flow, you're providing a credit card,
the networks aren't always huge fans of on ramping into crypto. So maybe you're actually providing
a debit card, you know, or you're connecting your bank, you're sort of making this movement happen,
you're learning the network as you go. It's one of the biggest gaps that's out there.
I actually think that a lot of folks globally won't really have to on ramp in that way in the future.
I expect that they will start to gain access to stablecoins more through some other type of payout,
right? Just like the way that we get money today, I would expect employers to start offering payments
in stablecoins and that to be the method by which, for example, an average employee in Laddam
like receives access to their first stablecoin. You know, when we look at like the payons and
payouts, marketplaces that are operating on Stripe, right? These are basically giant systems of
distribution for stablecoins globally. I just don't, I don't think the world we're in today is really
a sustainable one. And I wonder often how long will be in the hybrid space? You know, I'd like to,
it's always easier to think to the future and say, oh, great, when we're all just on what we are
today, which is, you know, basically is Wi-Fi everywhere and we get to take the internet for
granted. Like, when do we stop having to have a phone number that we have to call for dial-up?
Unfortunately, I don't think we're going to be there tomorrow. And I do think that
it's going to be primarily powered, you know, in the extreme short term, you know, by
some of these really interesting organizations that are growing that are kind of consolidating
the on and off ramps, especially in most difficult countries. So, yellow card is a really interesting
example here, right? That is it's run by Chris Maurice and he is, he's creating these on and off
ramp with all of the local financial institutions all across Africa, which would otherwise be very
difficult, right? Very difficult for a company to go show up over there and make each one of
these integrations and relationships such that they can start to on and off ramp. That will then
provide a lot of the liquidity access in and out to the businesses that will then be making the
payouts or otherwise to consumers or other merchants. So, I think it's a little bit of a roundabout
way of thinking about it, right? It's not that like the average on ramp is just going to get better.
It's that you probably won't need an on ramp in the future. It's probably more likely that you'll
simply have stablecoins as an option in another way that you would be acquiring money. At the limit,
your bank is hopefully just providing it as an option as a payout as well. But probably in the
short term, it's much more likely to be coming from, say, your merchant account at Stripe.
So, if you're taking payments in, we've been talking a lot about stablecoin payments
that come in and settle as dollars. Well, the other way around is just as interesting
as you're taking payments and in local currencies, but you're settling them instead to stablecoins.
Those types of capabilities, I think, will actually drive consumer holding and adoption
far faster than kind of these windows apps that we have today for on and off ramping,
especially with the consumer layer. And we're seeing this happen really fast at major financial
institutions, right? I think the bidle fund is a good example of a non-stablecoin, but rapidly
growing on-chain asset that will just be much more native in terms of how it will pay out or pay in
from stablecoins. I think things like that will just propagate these coins across the commercial
world, and then that will then propagate to the consumer space. I hope that answers. It's a little
bit of a roundabout way of saying kind of what it is. I think it'll be a different method by
which people get access to these things versus an improvement on the existing system.
Yeah. I mean, you're completely right in that if there's more net inflows than outflows,
then the entire stablecoin space will become less reliant on future inflows. I think there's still a
very wide spectrum of on-ramping experiences, right? If you kind of look at the very,
I mean, yeah, kind of like you can on-ramp with a credit card typically that's very expensive,
kind of like often kind of like people go via centralized exchanges, so kind of they do KYC
with the centralized exchange. They kind of send fear to the centralized exchanges,
bank account, and then they kind of off-ramp into the decentralized space on the other side.
Clearly, that's a terrible experience, but kind of we've seen kind of the rise of
these on-ramping tools. So, for instance, in Europe, we have Monareum, which kind of lets you
identify your wallet with an i-band. You kind of send euros to that i-band and within 20 seconds.
It's magic. It shows up in your wallet. Obviously, and at zero fees, because it's priced into their
business model, because they get custody of your euros, so kind of obviously there's some sort of
yield play here. We see the same thing in principle with picks integrations in Brazil,
or even in the US, their players know are now, which kind of offer this kind of
this kind of service. What are your thoughts on these?
So, if you look at like bridge and virtual accounts and like stablecoin financial accounts,
very similar, right? Like access to these integrations between the traditional and crypto
financial rails. So, with like a stablecoin financial account, you get an i-band as well.
You get an ACH, a routing number, right, and an account number that you can move ACH or wire into.
I think that it's a really important step towards integrating, especially on the commercial side,
how businesses move this money in and out. And I think it's a core principle to the idea that
I'm just trying to access what the stablecoin represents. I think we kind of come back to this
idea of like, what is the conviction? Is the conviction to hold a stablecoin or is the conviction
to hold a dollar? And if the conviction is to hold a dollar, then you're going to expect dollar-like
rails, or if the conviction is to store euro, the expectations of euro rails. And then what's
actually backing the thing that you're holding is almost irrelevant, right? So, this is, I think,
what these kinds of on and off ramps are encouraging is this idea that you can make the stablecoin
act from a rails standpoint, just like the fiat currency that you're otherwise accustomed to.
And over time, we expect this to become more invisible, right? You won't really be talking
about how, oh, I can use ACH to on ramp into a stablecoin. You'll just be saying, I can use ACH
again to dollars. But then the organization that's doing that is maybe using a bridge virtual account
on the back end. And what they're actually doing, right, is they're storing USDV, you know, or maybe
a custom stablecoin that they've minted, right? But to the user, it can just feel like dollars.
And so I think that that's maybe like the next evolution in the on ramp from sort of the classic
consumer. Let's go use a credit card in this very explicit, I am on ramping experience. Over to,
I'm accessing a currency type I wish I had. And I'm utilizing the rails that I'm otherwise accustomed
to. I think if you take it one step farther, we'd hope that those rails kind of disappear.
I don't, I don't, I don't, I don't, in Europe, you all have much better like systems for sort
of I bands and rapid movement. But like the ACH network is not, is not like positively thought of
in the US is like a wonderful way to move money around. You know, we think much more in apps here,
you know, we think about, you know, what's, you know, you have Venmo, you know, do you have PayPal,
like for especially for consumer to consumer experience. So I think a lot more of those products
will be powered by stablecoin backing. And they'll have the access to that rail for on ramping and
off ramping, but it'll all happen very much behind the scenes. You made two very big strategic
acquisitions this year, namely Bridge and Privy. Talk us through kind of like what both of them do
and how they complement what stripes, stripe already had before. Right. So very excited, by the way,
about about both of these. I can't comment very deeply on on the Privy front. That's that's sort
of an in progress acquisition. But on on bridge. Listen, first of all, the bridge team is just
incredible. Like fantastic group of executors who have been working in the stablecoin space
exclusively. And you think about kind of first mover and second mover advantages like bridge came
in and started to build with a very clean philosophy towards we are going to go and engage and make
stablecoins as magical as stripe was able to do for sort of the traditional finance world. I'm not
100% sure. I think at one point, even on their website, I think they described themselves as the
stripe of stablecoins. But listen, they what what what what what Bridge really does is they've really
optimized this API experience to access all of the underlying power of stablecoins. And they've done
this with these virtual accounts, which power things like what you were describing in terms of
being able to move in and out of traditional finance rails into stablecoins for organizations.
They've really created wonderful orchestration systems for being able to command movement of
these stablecoins. They've optimized a pretty pretty exciting set of on and off ramps that
you and I were talking about a little bit, but they've made them all abstracted away. So if
you're trying to get out into a local network, maybe you're using like, you know, one of these
crypto exchanges or partners in the back end, but you don't have to know that, you're just running
a command to pull the money out into a local account. And I think they're just iterating
really successfully in that space and executing with some of the most interesting organizations
in the world. I love the SpaceX example. I think it's just like it's one of these unique
capable like examples of treasury management that it would just would look like a phone book of,
you know, processes and money movement and decision making to do in the traditional finance world.
But with Bridge, it's just an API call. And so I think Bridge has really just been
on that forefront. And for Stripe, being able to leverage an internal infrastructure partner
is just step function impact for the organization. I think, you know, if you look historically,
we mostly used external partners for stablecoin access, liquidity management orchestration.
And so it was very natural, I think, to find, you know, who believe is the best in the industry
to bring in to our organization. And certainly for my team, who's operating, you know, primarily
on the product build side, you know, it's just was was like hitting hitting the easy button across
the ability to go and make these products happen now with an in-house partner. And so I think,
I think most natural and obvious acquisition out there for us. And obviously very exciting,
I think, for the crypto world to see Stripe leaning in that deeply, but also just the validation,
I think, of that space in general. Privy, again, I can't go super deep into Privy.
I think Privy is doing some really amazing things with just general decentralized wallet
access and non-custodial wallets. And there's a lot of interesting opportunity there.
But I'll leave it at that. I think there's a lot of future news to come out on that front.
Yeah. I have rather philosophical question to kind of end on kind of when the web
three movement kind of started. It was very much in the vein that kind of like these will be kind of
better. It will be peer to peer kind of money. It will make kind of big financial players
redundant, kind of like people will kind of be able to kind of do things
on their own by themselves. And now kind of to some degree, to a large degree, it's kind of
morphed into kind of just giving more efficient and resilient tools to the mountain, right? So
kind of like large financial institutions kind of now use these rates to kind of kind of reap
efficiency gains. How do you see that kind of in the larger picture kind of like coming
somewhat from the other side? Yeah. I don't think I'm coming from the other side, first of all.
But I think I've gone back and reread the Bitcoin white paper a couple of times. I think it's easy
to put different lenses on that statement, right? But what we're really trying to build is some
sort of a peer to peer system of cash transfer, right? That's open and accessible to anyone
and does not require an authority in the middle for it to exist, right? And just a very simple kind
of set of capabilities. And I think any system that's developed that permits you to have
infinite, you know, optionality, right, will certainly spawn versions of itself that do have,
you know, centralized actors. And those will be adopted, I think, where they're most
beneficial to the to the users. And so like my example a minute ago, I think is a good one. I
think while kind of the barter system of like, I have cash in my back pocket and I've walked into
the town square, has great optionality of the types of things I could maybe trade for and the
types of engagements, you know, that maybe I wouldn't traditionally have access to. Like,
I also just want to go to Amazon and like buy, you know, paperclips or, or, or, or, you know, a
light bulb or something that I need. And in those experiences and in those transactions,
I think there's a lot of, there's a lot of like, just expectation from consumers today
about the types of protections and, and sort of management of the payment. And they don't really
need to know what's happening under the hood and they don't really need to hold the dollar in their
hand. So I just, I don't, I've never felt like these two things are particularly deeply at odds
with each other. I think that like one is simply an iteration or a branch of the other. And I guess
you could argue that in the traditional space, maybe we've started to lose the first a little bit.
Because the history of money is also pretty decently decentralized and open, right? As we all,
we all sort of have dollars in our back pocket and where we're going and purchasing things from,
you know, our neighbors or other other people who are, who are selling something and weren't
making a value transaction. And this really wasn't too much of a middleman and they're
except backing, right, the value of the dollar itself. And I think the reason a lot of that has
sort of has shifted has been to do with like scale and like trust and kind of expectations
of additional services that are built on top of it that maybe aren't available.
But I think, I think we'll just blockchain and stablecoins, they'll push us steps towards the
advantages of like peer to peer networks, hopefully without also absorbing like the downsides.
And this is this is what I was getting out a minute ago, which is like a lot of these
kind of consumer trust assurances can likely be built on chain. I was at a conference pretty
recently, I think, I think salon accelerate. And someone was asking me, you know, what, what, you
know, what other startups ought to exist, you know, what should people be building? And very much,
you know, the statement here is with like a disruptive technology like crypto, like all of this stuff
gets to be rebuilt, like who gets to define what it is to do, often capture who gets to define what
it is to do a refund, you know, who gets to define what it is to make a real estate transaction,
like there are just endless iterations of commercial actions that you might, you know,
describe today as primarily centralized, right, like buying a house is a great example. I'm not
sure what it's like in Germany, but in the US buying a house, right? This is very like centralized
process. And I think having the capability to do it entirely in a non centralized way actually
probably lands us where most people get somewhere closer to the center, where we lose a lot of the
downsides of like an extremely centralized system, but we don't maybe absorb 100% of the risk of an
entirely decentralized system. So I think both sides of the barbell are necessary to kind of get to
the future world that we want. And I guess, I guess that's sort of my answer to that. I think
there's a I don't I don't think stripe or most actors are really philosophically opposed to either
side. I think what we're looking for is, you know, what are the best capabilities of this
technology? And how do we expose it to the people who are trying to run their businesses and make
their purchases every day? Famous last words. Thank you so much, John, for coming on. It's been a
a pleasure. For sure. Thanks for having me.